<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The humble petition and representation of many inhabitants of the county of Buckingham, concerning the late votes passed, touching no farther address to the King, presented to the Honorable House of Commons, March the ninth, 1647. With an Order of the Commons assembled in Parliament, in approbation of the said petition. Ordered by the Commons assembled in Parliament, that this petition with the Order be forthwith printed and published. H: Elsynge, Cler. Parl. D. Com.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 6KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 5 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A86753</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99865324</idno>
  <idno type="VID">117563</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240919884</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing H3440</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Thomason E432_12</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R206146</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99865324</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99865324e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A86753)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 117563)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Thomason Tracts ; 68:E432[12])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The humble petition and representation of many inhabitants of the county of Buckingham, concerning the late votes passed, touching no farther address to the King, presented to the Honorable House of Commons, March the ninth, 1647. With an Order of the Commons assembled in Parliament, in approbation of the said petition. Ordered by the Commons assembled in Parliament, that this petition with the Order be forthwith printed and published. H: Elsynge, Cler. Parl. D. Com.</title>
                  <author>England and Wales. Parliament.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>8 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for Edward Husband, Printer to the Honorable House of Commons,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>March 15. 1647 [i.e. 1648]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="personal_name">Charles --  I, --  King of England, 1600-1649 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="geographic_name">Great Britain --  History --  Civil War, 1642-1649 --  Treaties --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="geographic_name">Buckinghamshire (England) --  History --  17th century --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-05 </date>
            <label>John Pas </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-05 </date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:117563:1"/>
            <p>The Humble PETITION AND Representation of many Inhabi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tants of the County of <hi>BƲCKINGHAM,</hi> Concerning The late Votes passed, touching no farther Address to the KING, Presented to the Honourable House of Commons, <hi>March</hi> the Ninth, 1647.</p>
            <p>WITH And Order of the Commons assem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bled in Parliament, in approba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of the said Petition.</p>
            <q>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                  <body>
                     <div type="license">
                        <p>ORdered by the Commons assembled in Parliament, That this Petition with the Order be forthwith Printed and Published.</p>
                        <closer>
                           <signed>H: Elsynge, Cler. Parl. D. Com.</signed>
                        </closer>
                     </div>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
            </q>
            <p>
               <hi>London,</hi> Printed for <hi>Edward Husband,</hi> Printer to the Honorable House of Commons. <hi>March</hi> 15. 1647.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="petition">
            <pb facs="tcp:117563:2"/>
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:117563:2"/>
            <head>To the Honorable, the House of Commons assembled in Parliament: <hi>The humble Petition and Representation of many of the Inhabitants of the County of Buckingham,</hi>
            </head>
            <opener>SHEWETH,</opener>
            <p>THat the many Glorious Vi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctories and Successes where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>with God hath Crowned your faithful endeavors for the good of this Kingdom, being so clear a manifestation of his wisdom, power and care, against the fraud and force of all your enemies: Your Petitio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners should justly incur the Cen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sure of perpetual Infamy, if they should now requite your unwearied
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:117563:3"/>pains with Ingratitude and Disserti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on: And having with joy observed your Resolution to go on in your Honorable endeavors for the Pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>like benefit of this Kingdom, by your late Proceedings in taking a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>way the heavy burthen of Free-quarter, reducing your Forces, and setling your ever faithful Army (whom your Petitioners cannot mention without thankfulness, for that measure of Freedom they enjoy through their fidelity and valor) in such a condition of charge, as the publique safety may admit. And in your late Votes &amp; Declaration con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerning the King (after his rejecting so many Applications) having so fully cleared your selves, as may
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:117563:3"/>stop the mouth of Envy and Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lignity it self for ever.</p>
            <p>Your Petitioners therefore in Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stimony of their Duty and Cordial affection, do humbly tender their hearty thanks for all your care and pains in the preservation of their In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terests against the strongest opposi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of Malignants and Apostates you have met with; and do humbly Represent unto your Honors their faithful Resolutions, by Gods assi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stance, to adhere unto, and stand by you in the further prosecution ther<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of against all opposers: and do hum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bly desire that you will proceed to a speedy setling of the civil Govern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, in such a way as may most conduce to the freedom and happi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ness
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:117563:4"/>of this Nation: To put forth your power for the promotion of Religion, according to the word of God: To give due encouragement to all godly and able Ministers, and to cast out such as are scandalous and unfit for the work of the Ministery: To be tender of the Consciences of such whose conversations are as becometh the Gospel of Christ; To consider seriously of the deplo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rable condition of their Brethren in <hi>Ireland,</hi> and to send them such seaso<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nable relief and ayd, that the streams of their blood may be dryed up, and those Barbarous blood-thirsty Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bels rewarded according to the mea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sure of their cruelties: To take care for your secure sitting against
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:117563:4"/>outward force and violence, and to punish the Authors, Printers, and Publishers of all wicked and scan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dalous Pamphlets, who privily instil into the breasts of many, a sinister conceit, and misinterpretation of all your noble actions and under<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>takings, and endeavour to blast the Loyal affections of all that faithfully adhere unto you: To take care for the easing of those Counties, as pay beyond their proportion of Taxes with others, and to go on with cou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rage still to redress what ever else shall be found to be a grievance to this Nation. So shall the Lord of Hosts go before you, and make plain all mountains that shall ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>struct your way, and give you Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nor
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:117563:5"/>and answerable success in your further undertakings. And your Pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>titioners and many others seeing the further accomplishment of their de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sires, shall the more chearfully pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceed to hazard their lives and For<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tunes in your assistance;</p>
            <closer>
               <hi>And shall ever pray,</hi> &amp;c.</closer>
         </div>
         <div type="response_to_petition">
            <head>Die Jovis, 9. Martii, 1647.</head>
            <p>THe House being informed that divers Gentlement of the County of <hi>Buckingham</hi> were at the door, desiring to prefer a Petition to this House, They were called in, and <hi>Mr. Egleton,</hi> with divers others did prefer a Petition, Entituled, <hi>The hum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble Petition &amp; Representation of many of the Inhabitants of the county of</hi> Buckingham, the which was read and it is ordred by the Commons assembled in Parliament, That <hi>Mr. Speaker,</hi> by the Command of this House, do take notice of their former and still continued Constant, Faithful, and good Services and Affections to the Parliament, and that he return them the ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry hearty thanks of this House for the same; and acquaint them, That this House hath Ordered their Petition to be Printed, to the end their early and continued good affections may be pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liquely taken notice of to their Honor and the furter satisfa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction and encouragement of others: And that the house hath appointed to take their Petition into consideration in conveni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ent time.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>H: Elsynge, Cler. Parl. D. Com.</signed>
            </closer>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>